Putri.Y. Utami, S.Pd., M.Li

Umbulharjo, Yogyakarta, Indonesia | P: <u>+62 85745254350 |</u>
putriyuniutami14@gmail.com | contact@putriyuniutami.site | www.linkedin.com/in/putri-yuni-utami/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly skilled and experienced in writing, translating, transcribing, and proofreading, with a strong command of English, Indonesian, and Javanese languages. Bringing extensive experience in translating written documents and audio recordings, as well as providing impeccable proofreading, editing, and writing services.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

<u>Life Management Science Labs</u>

2023 - Present

Technical Editor

- Interpreting research handover documents and writing standard documents appropriate for the intended audience based on the handovers.
- Producing 4 high-quality standard documents per month based on research handovers.
- Collaborating with Junior and Senior Researchers for standard document production and to ensure document accuracy.
- Reviewing and improving 4 technical documents monthly for clarity, grammar, spelling, punctuation, content, and style
- Creating standard document templates for other technical editors that are easy to apply and adapt.
- Ensuring that 95% of the technical content on the company website is up-to-date, with monthly updates.
- Providing feedback and advice to researchers

Origin Hope Media Group Limited

2022 - 2023

Subcontractor Content Writer

- Writing over 15.000 words of relevant content per day for blog articles, news articles, product descriptions, or promo and video scripts.
- Conducting thorough research for more than 2 hours a day on industry-related topics, and generating ideas for new content types.
- Creating compelling copies for the landing pages of websites for more than 5 clients.
- Collaborating with other writers to produce over 20 articles a day or over 100 articles a week

Fienyx Translation 2017 - Present

Chief Editor and Translator

- Providing technical translation services for more than 4 major professional fields including legal translation, academic translation, and subtitling.
- Discussing translation requirements with clients, and determining any fees to be charged for language services provided to improve 25% efficiency.
- Utilizing current translation software to increase the efficiency of proofreading, editing, and revising translated materials by 30%
- Using various reference materials as needed to establish the accuracy of translation and localization.
- Checking original texts or conferring with authors to guarantee that translations retain 95% of the original material's content, meaning, and feeling.
- Checking technical terms and terminology translations to ensure that they are at least 95% accurate and consistent across translation revisions.

Putri.Y. Utami, S.Pd., M.Li

Umbulharjo, Yogyakarta, Indonesia | P: <u>+62 85745254350 |</u> putriyuniutami14@gmail.com | contact@putriyuniutami.site | www.linkedin.com/in/putri-yuni-utami/

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PT. IZPAL Investama Properti

2021 - 2022

Mortgage Finance and Back Office Human Resource

- Designed and developed adaptable administrative and human resources systems to increase efficiency and productivity by 35%.
- Established document management processes to maintain a database of over 5.000 potential customers.
- Managed all paperwork generated by salespeople for 45 customers, including payment processing, consumers' mortgage information, and personal details.
- Supported the managing director, vice president, managers, and supervisors in meeting deadlines, managing customer visits, and organizing company's events.
- Organized invitations for a successful Open House event for 300+ people to secure buyer interest.
- Coordinated mailing of over 50 formal letters and information packets monthly.
- Screened and recruited over 100 qualified potential candidates.
- Updated 20+ employee records and job assignments on a regular basis.
- Scheduled candidates and conducted first-round interviews via telephonic conversation for candidates across 5 roles.

EDUCATION

Universitas Sebelas Maret

2015 - 2019

Masters of Art in Linguistics Majoring in Translation

Cumulative GPA: 3.78/4.0

Relevant Coursework: Proofreading, Qualitative Research, Philosophy of Science, Text Editing, English Grammar, Linguistics, Sociolinguistics, Semantics, Functional Grammar, Contrastive Analysis, Systemic Functional Linguistics, Discourse Analysis, Cross-Cultural Pragmatics, Genre Based Translation, Legal Translation, Technical Translation, Intercultural Communication.

Universitas Ahmad Dahlan

2009-2014

Bachelor of English Language Education

Cumulative GPA: 3.73/4.0

Relevant Coursework: Literary Theory, Creative Writing, Journalism, Storytelling, Curriculum Development, Classroom Management, Lesson Planning, Literacy, Teacher Training, Public Speaking, Teamwork, Organization Skills, Teaching English as a Foreign Language, Listening Comprehension, Instructional Technology, English for Specific Purpose, Business Letter, Applied Linguistics

OTHERS

Technical Skills: Adobe Audition, Basic Web Programmer (CSS & HTML), Copywriting, Transcribing, Customer Support, GIMP, GitHub, Human Resources (HR), Linux Operation System, Personal Branding, Operations Management, Office Administration Web Content Writing, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Creative Strategy, Strategic Communications, Content Development, Traditional Drawing, Visual Studio Code, Administration, Executive Administrative Assistance, Data Entry, Spreadsheets, Time Management

Certifications & Training: PASAS ® Certified International Specialist in Data Engineering (CISDE), Participant Training for Fundamental Steps to be A Web Programmer Hosted by HACKTIV8 Indonesia, Participant of Bengkel Penerjemahan, Ministry of Education and Culture.

Languages: Javanese, Indonesian (Native), English (Fluent)

